aptana.org 2016-06-15

# Aptana | Privacy Policy

### Introduction

Aptana Inc. values an individual's right to personal privacy as much as we value our own privacy. We will collect and use information through our website (" **Site** ") and in connection with our products (" **Products** ") and services (" **Services** ") only in the ways disclosed in this statement. We will not sell your Personal Information or share it with other parties, unless necessary, as dictated by abuse, or except in the particular circumstances described below. This statement applies solely to information collected at our Site or in connection with use of our Products and Services, including Aptana Studio and the Aptana Cloud Service. 

Each Customer of Aptana's Cloud Service may develop its own website or online services (" **Customer Site** ") using the Cloud Service. When you visit a Customer Site, the Customer Site may collect and use information about you (" **Customer Collected Information** "). Except to the extent stated below, this Privacy Policy does not govern or limit collection or use of Customer Collected Information. You are responsible for reviewing the privacy policy on each Customer Site you visit. Except to the extent stated below, we have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, any Customer Site, its content, or its collection and use of Customer Collected Information. 

**By using this Site and the Products and Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, you agree and acknowledge that Personal Information collected through the Site or in connection with the Products and Services may be transferred across national boundaries and stored and processed in any of the countries around the world in which Aptana maintains offices, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of Personal Information may be less stringent than the laws in your country. We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors who are under the age of 13.**

### Information collection

" **Personal Information** " means information that allows someone to identify or contact you, including, for example, your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, as well as any other non-public information about you that is associated with or linked to any of the foregoing information. As a visitor to this Site, you can engage in many activities without providing any Personal Information. 

In connection with other activities, such as utilizing online or hosted Products and Services, Aptana may ask you to provide certain information about yourself by filling out and submitting a form. This is optional. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, Aptana may ask you to provide Personal Information, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including ZIP code), country of residence, email address, employer, job title and department, telephone and facsimile numbers, and other Personal Information. When ordering Products and Services via the Site, you may be asked to provide a credit card number. If you provide us feedback, contact us via e-mail, participate in one of our surveys, or submit a support request via our website, we may collect additional Personal Information, such as your name and email address, and any information that you submit to us. Depending upon the activity, some of the information that we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity. We may also receive information about you from other sources such as telephone or fax, or from our third party service providers and our contractors. 

When you use the Site and the Products and Services, Aptana may also collect certain information about your computer to facilitate, improve, and evaluate your use of the Site and the Products and Services. For example, we may log the number of downloads, types of Services used, how many users we receive daily, and environmental variables, such as browser type, operating system, CPU speed, referring or exit web pages, and the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer (" **Usage Information** "). Aptana also uses Usage Information to measure traffic patterns on the Site and usage of the Products and Services. 

### Information usage

Aptana collects your information in order to record, support, and facilitate your use of the Site, Products, and Services, including your participation in the activities you select; improve our Site, Product and Services; send you responses to your requests or inquiries; and send you promotional communications or solicit your feedback. If you subscribe to or register for Products and Services, for example, the information is used to register your rights, if any, to technical support or other benefits that may be made available to registered users. As another example, if you enter a contest, information is collected to qualify the entry and to contact you regarding the contest or prize awards. 

Aptana may use aggregate Usage Information for improving the Site, Products, and Services, providing more relevant experiences to our customers, and/or for statistical analysis. If you order the Aptana Cloud Service, Aptana may collect Usage Information about visitor's of your Customer Site, and may associate such Usage Information with your Customer Site. Aptana may use such Usage Information to promote your Customer Site. 

### Information choices

Aptana recognizes and appreciates the importance of responsible use of information collected on the Site and in connection with the Products and Services. Aptana will respect your legal rights regarding access to and correction and deletion of your Personal Information. 

You may change the Personal Information in your account with Aptana by editing your profile within the account. You may request deletion of your account information by us, but please note that we may be required (by law or otherwise) to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete account information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives. 

We may periodically send you free newsletters and promotional e-mails. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive. Despite your indicated e-mail preferences, we may continue to send you administrative emails in connection with your use of the Site, Products, or Services, unless you terminate your account with Aptana. 

### Information disclosure

Except in the particular circumstances described in this Privacy Policy, Aptana will not provide your name to other companies or organizations without your consent. 

There are other instances in which Aptana may divulge your Personal Information, such as where required by law or legal process, regulation, security reasons, or litigation, or to protect or defend the rights or property of Aptana or other users of the Site, Products, or Services. 

We may share your Personal Information with third party service providers and our contractors for the sole purpose of providing the Site, Products and Services to you. These third parties are required to not use your Personal Information other than provide the services requested by Aptana. 

Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other affiliates, we may in the future. We may share some or all of your Personal Information with these parties, in which case we will require them to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires our company or our assets, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by it and us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Aptana reserves the right to use and disclose aggregate, non-identifying Information to third parties in its discretion. 

### Information protection

The Personal Information that you provide in connection with registering yourself as a user of the Site or of the Products and Services is classified as " **Registration Information** ". Registration Information is protected in several ways. Access by you to your Registration Information is available through a password and unique customer ID selected by you. This password is encrypted. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. In addition, your Registration Information resides on servers to which Aptana only provides access to select personnel and contractors via password. Aptana encrypts your Personal Information and thereby strives to prevent unauthorized parties from viewing such information when it is transmitted to Aptana. 

Personal Information that you provide that does not constitute Registration Information also resides on servers to which Aptana only provides access to select Aptana personnel and contractors via password. Since this information is not accessible online by you, you will not be asked to select a password in order to view or modify such information. 

Despite these measures, you should know that Aptana cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information. 

Please note that any information you post to a public bulletin board, blog or chat room, such as the Aptana Forums is available to all persons accessing that location, and your e-mail address may also be posted on these venues. The information you share, including your email address, would then be available to all persons accessing these venues, and such information may be read, collected or used by others for any purpose, including sending you unsolicited messages. Aptana is not responsible for any information you elect to submit in these venues or the use of such information. 

If you order the Aptana Cloud Service, Aptana may retain materials, data, or information provide by you, others who have access to your account, or visitors of your Customer Site (defined below) and used in connection with the Aptana Cloud Service and/or your Customer Site. Based on your account settings, such materials, data, or information may be accessed by any individual with access to the internet or only a limited group of individuals. 

### Information tracking

In order to improve our Products and Services and the Site and provide more convenient, relevant experiences to our customers, we and our vendors may use "cookies", "web beacons", and similar devices to track your activities. A cookie is small amount of data that is transferred to your browser by a web server and can only be read by the server that gave it to you. It functions as your identification card and enables Aptana to record your passwords, purchases, and preferences. It cannot be executed as code or deliver viruses. A web beacon is a small transparent gif image that is embedded in an HTML page or email used to track when the page or email has been viewed. A similar device may be used by which a Product and Service may send data to a server when a set of user-initiated events occur such as the "Proceed to Checkout" button is clicked. This device is similar to a cookie in that it tracks your visit and the data can only be read by the server that receives the data. It is different than a cookie in that it is not browser-based, may not function as an identification card, and does not store any data on your computer. 

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, and most Products and Services that include similar devices are typically initially activated to collect data. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. (For some web pages that require an authorization, cookies are not optional. Users choosing not to accept cookies or similar devices will probably not be able to access those pages or the related Products and Services.) 

Certain Products and Services may require you to use the most current version of such Product and Service or are offered in conjunction with other Products and Services, which you may or may not have already downloaded. The Product and Service may automatically check to determine if you are using the most current version or have other Products and Services and through e-mail messages, pop-up boxes or similar mechanisms inform you if need to upgrade in order to use the Product and Service you have requested. During this process, an IP address identifying your computer and the Product and Service version may be sent to a web server along with Usage Information. 

### Websites of Aptana's Customers

As part of our Cloud Service, Aptana will store Customer Collected Information for each Customer Site. Aptana will store such Customer Collected Information on servers to which Aptana only provides access to select Aptana personnel and contractors via password and to the Customer and individuals authorized by the Customer. Aptana will encrypt such information. 

As noted above, Aptana may collect Usage Information about visitor's of your Customer Site, and may associate such Usage Information with your Customer Site. Aptana may use such Usage Information to promote your Customer Site. 

Aptana may also divulge Customer Collected Information in the particular circumstances described in the section titled "Information Disclosure" above, such as, without limitation, where required by law or legal process, regulation, security reasons, or litigation, or to protect or defend the rights or property of Aptana or other users of the Site, Products, or Services. 

### Third-party websites

Our provision of a link to any other website or location, such as payment processing websites, is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other website or location or its contents. When you click on such a link, you will leave our Site and go to another site. During this process, a third party may collect information from you. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of data after you click on a link to a third party. 

### Contact information

Aptana welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at [info@aptana.com](mailto:info@aptana.com) or contact us at the headquarters address or main phone number on our Contact page. 

Aptana may provide you notices under this Privacy Policy by sending you an email to the email address you provided to us. 

### Changes to Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is subject to occasional revision, and if we make any substantial changes in the way we use your Personal Information, we will notify you and/or prominently post notice of the changes on our Site. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon the earlier of thirty (30) calendar days following our notice to you or thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on our Site. These changes will be effective immediately for new users of our Site, Products, or Services or upon renewal or new order of a Product or Service. Please note that at all times you are responsible for updating your Personal Information to provide us with your most current e-mail address. In the event that the last e-mail address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the e-mail containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice. In any event, changes to this Privacy Policy may affect our use of Personal Information that you provided us prior to our notification to you of the changes. If you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your Personal Information, you must notify us prior to the effective date of the changes that you wish to deactivate your account with us. Continued use of our Site, Product or Service, following notice of such changes, shall indicate your acknowledgment of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes. 

This Privacy Policy was last revised on May 28, 2009.
